#### Katia Pechenkina

### Student journalist

- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ekaterina-pechenkina-1a8360145/
- Twitter: https://twitter.com/KatiaPechenkina

I am a first-year graduate student at Philip Merrill College of Journalism at the University of Maryland. I have experience in writing for a college newspaper, anchoring, producing and editing video for a student-produced weekly news show. I was also a part of Democracy and the Informed citizen emerging journalist fellowship program.

# **Experience:**

Journalism Fellow

Democracy and the Informed citizen emerging journalist fellowship program, California humanities

February 2021 – June 2021

With a team of three other fellows reported on the disproportionate impact of COVID-19 on National City's smallest Latinx-owned businesses. As a team we produced a <u>multimedia project</u> that brought together an enterprise story with interactives and data visualizations, five small business profiles, a podcast featuring the mayor, a video story and photo gallery.

Multimedia Journalist

Newscene, San Diego City College

February 2021 – May 2021

I was a weekly contributor to the student-produced <u>TV news broadcast</u>, where I alternated between different broadcasting positions including anchoring, producing, editing and writing. I pitched 2-5 stories a week and wrote 2-3 scripts per show in broadcast style on deadline. I also took part in promoting the show content on social media (Twitter, Instagram, YouTube, Facebook).

**News Editor** 

City Times, San Diego City College

August 2020 – May 2021

I was a part of a 25-student staff producing news content five days a week for the digitally-driven student news website serving the 16,000-student campus of City College. Led coverage of the impact of COVID-19 on the Latino community in San Diego County, localizing the story with as interview of a campus health official and data specific to the campus, a Hispanic Serving

Institution. I also covered local elections in November 2020, and focused on the <u>competitive</u> race for the 50th District on Election Day.

#### **Education:**

- Bachelor of Arts, International relations, Moscow State Lomonosov University, 2017
- Master of Journalism, Philip Merrill College of Journalism, University of Maryland, August 2021 - Present

# Skills:

- Strong analytical skills and experience with research assignments
- Trained in writing and editing using Associated Press Stylebook as a guide
- Exposed to multimedia production techniques, including audio editing and web-based layout and graphic design
- Basic video editing skills using Adobe Premier
- Fluent in Russian